beeline.com 2018-04-16

# Beeline VMS & Contingent Workforce Solutions—Privacy Policy

## BACKGROUND

Beeline provides services procurement and payment automation solutions for large international enterprises. As part of its process management services, Beeline obtains and processes Personal Data on behalf of customers. In addition, Beeline obtains Personal Data of website visitors who request to receive marketing materials via email. This Privacy Policy describes Beeline’s commitment to privacy and the procedures and policies to protect all the Personal Data in Beeline’s possession.

Under this Privacy Policy and the embodied procedures and policies, Beeline complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States.  Beeline has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles.  If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Beeline commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information.  EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact [privacy@beeline.com](mailto:privacy@beeline.com).

Beeline has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to JAMs, an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the [United States]. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please email [privacy@beeline.com](mailto:privacy@beeline.com) for more information or to file a complaint.  The services of JAMs are provided at no cost to you.

This Privacy Policy was last changed on December 2017.

## DEFINITIONS

Personal Data refers to any information that is identifiable to specific individuals or by which specific individuals can be identified, such as name, identification numbers, email address, mailing address, phone numbers, or other personal characteristics or attributes.

Personal Data does not include information that is previously publicly available or is anonymous statistical information that is not identifiable to a specific individual.

Data Subjects refers to the individuals to whom the Personal Data refers.

Data Controller refers to the owner of the data, which in most cases is the customer of IQN. When the Data Controller is a Beeline customer using Customer Confidential Information, Beeline performs the role of Data Processor.

Customer Confidential Information refers to non-public information that is proprietary to our customers and when the IQN customer is the Data Controller.

## PRIVACY PRINCIPLES

Beeline is committed to individual privacy and recognizes its responsibility for protecting the Personal Data in its possession and care. The Beeline Privacy Policy is embodied in the following principles:

**For Customer Confidential Information, the following will apply:**

For other purposes where Beeline is Data Controller

Notice: Data Subjects should be notified at the time of data collection regarding what Personal Data is collected, how it will be used, and to whom it will be disclosed by the Data Controller.

This Privacy Policy will be published prominently on Beeline’s website as well as via communications with Data Subjects, such as upon login to the Beeline software applications. This policy may change from time to time, in which case appropriate notifications will be provided.

Access: Data Subjects will be granted access to the Personal Data related to them, and will be able to submit corrections to the information where it is believed to be inaccurate (see “Inquiries” below). Corrections will be subject to verification and acceptance by the Data Controller.

_Data Integrity:_

In the event that a complaint is received, Beeline will take steps to ensure that the Personal Data is accurate and current.

_Onward Transfer and Choice:_

**For Customer Confidential Information, the following will apply:**

Beeline will not transfer Personal Data to third parties, other than the Data Controller or their designees and third parties who perform certain services for Beeline. All such parties agree to maintain appropriate procedures to safeguard the Personal Data and use it only for the purposes of providing services.

For other purposes where Beeline is the Data Controller, Beeline agrees to maintain appropriate procedures to safeguard the Personal Data and use it only for the purposes described in the collection notice and as the Data Controller directs.

If Beeline shares EU Personal Data with a third-party service provider that processes the data solely on Beeline’s behalf, then Beeline will be liable for that third party’s processing of EU Personal Data in violation of the Principles, unless Beeline can prove that we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

National Security or Law Enforcement Requirements: In the event that Beeline receives a lawful request to disclose personal information by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement needs, Beeline will comply with the request.

## SECURITY:

Beeline will treat all Personal Data as confidential and will maintain internal procedures and security safeguards designed to prevent inappropriate disclosure or misuse of Personal Data by Beeline staff.  Beeline personnel are responsible for protecting Personal Data and Customer Confidential information, are trained in the applicable policies, and are expected to adhere to the procedures and intent of this Privacy Policy.

Enforcement: Data Subjects who believe that their Personal Data was not handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy should contact Beeline’s Privacy Officer (see “Inquiries” below), who will conduct an investigation and report their findings to the Data Subject. European Union (EU) or Switzerland residents may also make use of the appropriate Data Protection Authorities; Beeline will cooperate with EU or Swiss Data Protection Authorities to investigate and resolve complaints, including complying with any resulting advice given by the Data Protection Authorities.

## POLICY PRACTICES

Information Collected

Beeline receives and stores nonpublic Personal Data and other Customer Confidential information from several sources in the normal course of business, including:

Identification and contact information from customers, their services suppliers, and the Data Subjects themselves.

Business process information (such as regarding services procurement and payment processes) through the usage of the Beeline applications and communications among customer users and their services suppliers, the Data Subjects, Beeline users, and third-party users.

Transaction and information system usage information from Beeline applications, Beeline websites, other contacts with Beeline, and third parties.

**Why This Information Is Collected**

For Customer Confidential Information:

  * Identifying the Data Subjects and associating their various authorized role(s) and preferences
  * Contacting and notifying Data Subjects of appropriate process events and data changes
  * Efficiently and accurately performing the process management services, including tasks as directed or authorized by the Data Controller.
  * Improve existing services and design new services.
  * Consequently, the Personal Data collected is generally contact information, identification information, and process-related transaction information.

**For other purposes where Beeline is Data Controller:**

Beeline uses cookies for a variety of reasons including, remembering registration information, to track whether or not you have already participated in a given survey, to autopopulate correspondence details. In some cases, Beeline will also collect correspondence information such as name, job title, company and email addresses in order to respond to inquiries about the application.

**How This Information Is Used**

Beeline uses Personal Data only for the purposes for which it was collected as described above.

In the normal course of business, Personal Data and Customer Confidential information is processed by Beeline and via third parties who are contracted to provide certain services to Beeline or customer.

Personal Data may also be transferred to third parties of the Data Controller and their authorized agents in the course of performing the process management services.

In addition, Beeline will perform legitimate and relevant tasks as directed or authorized by the Data Controller.

## INFORMATION SECURITY

Personal Data in Beeline’s possession is protected by its Information Systems Security Policy, which is designed to prevent unauthorized disclosure, misuse, or alteration of Personal Data. The Information Systems Security Policy includes confidentiality procedures applicable to all Beeline personnel, security requirements for physical and electronic security, and compliance policies and procedures for information handling. All Beeline personnel are required to acknowledge understanding of the Information Systems Security Policy, and adherence is enforced.

## INQUIRIES

To inquire about any aspect of this Privacy Policy, Personal Data held, or uses of the Personal Data, please contact the Beeline Privacy Officer via email at [privacy@beeline.com](mailto:privacy@beeline.com "Email privacy@beeline.com"), via telephone at +1-303-563-1500, or via mail to Beeline at 6465 Greenwood Plaza Boulevard, Suite 800, Centennial Colorado 80111 USA.

For inquiries from Data Subjects about their Personal Data, Beeline will forward the inquiries to the appropriate Data Controller and assist with resolving the inquiry, including providing access to the Personal Data and correcting any errors in cooperation with the Data Controller.

## PRIVACY SHEILD COMMITMENT

Beeline has committed to self-certification under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, and to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade commission (FTC). If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.

To view the list of companies who have committed to the Privacy Shield self-certification [click here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

## ALTERNATIVE DISPUTE RESOLUTION (ADR)

Beeline is committed to investigating and resolving all unresolved data privacy complaints in a timely manner. As such if Beeline is unable to resolve a complaint to the satisfaction of all parties, Beeline will provide free of charge access to an Alternative Dispute Resolution (ADR) provider.

To learn more about the terms in which Beeline is obligated to go through, and liable for binding arbitration under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield regulation, [click here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome).

To learn more about Beeline’s ADR, JAMS, [click here](https://www.jamsadr.com/about/submit-a-case).

Beeline will not sell personal information to mailing lists or share personal information to those who would use it for marketing purposes.

## COOKIE POLICY

#### What Are Cookies?

A cookie is a small text file that a website saves on your computer or mobile device when you visit the site. It enables the website to remember your actions and preferences (such as login, language, font size and other display preferences) over a period of time, so you don’t have to keep re-entering them whenever you come back to the site or browse from one page to another.

#### How We Use Cookies

We use cookies for a variety of reasons detailed below. Unfortunately in most cases there are no industry standard options for disabling cookies without completely disabling the functionality and features they add to this site. It is recommended that you leave on all cookies if you are not sure whether you need them or not in case they are used to provide a service that you use.

#### Disabling Cookies

You can prevent the setting of cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser (see your browser Help for how to do this). Be aware that disabling cookies will affect the functionality of this and many other websites that you visit. Disabling cookies will usually result in also disabling certain functionality and features of this site. Therefore it is recommended that you do not disable cookies.

#### Cookies We Set

This website does not set any cookies unless the user is logged in. These cookies do not contain any user information, and use a unique numeric value to verify the user’s login status and specific roles or permissions associated with the user.

#### Third Party Cookies

In some special cases we also use cookies provided by trusted third parties. The following section details which third party cookies you might encounter through this site.

  * #### Pardot.com

This website offers marketing and sales information about our products, and cookies may be for page performance and user viewing trends.  No personal information is stored or needed to provide Pardot.com with this information.

  * #### Google.com

This site uses Google Analytics which is one of the most widespread and trusted analytics solution on the web for helping us to understand how you use the site and ways that we can improve your experience. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site and the pages that you visit so we can continue to produce engaging content.

For more information on Google Analytics cookies, see the official [Google Analytics ](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)page.

  * #### Pingdom.com

This site uses a trusted third party service to monitor site activity and performance real time. Cookies are set with unique arbitrary values to track page performance and page activity; no user information is needed or stored during this process.

#### More Information

If you are still looking for more information you can contact us through one of our preferred contact methods.

Email: [privacy@beeline.com](mailto:privacy@beeline.com "Email privacy@beeline.com")

#### Further Information

Beeline has in place procedures for training employees in implementation of this Privacy Policy and disciplining them for failure to follow it. Beeline has in place internal procedures for periodically conducting objective reviews of compliance with our Privacy Policy. If you want to know more about our commitment to Privacy, please contact us at [privacy@beeline.com](mailto:privacy@beeline.com "Email privacy@beeline.com").
